{
  "version": 2.0,
  "questions": [
    {
      "question": "1. A  globular protein of size 30kDa exists as a monomer and dimer in solution. The most appropriate technique for separation of these two forms of protein is",
      "answers": {
        "a": "Size exclusion chromatography",
        "b": "Affinity chromatography",
        "c": "Ion-exchange chromatography",
        "d": "Hydrophobic chromatography"
      },
      
      "correctAnswer": "a",
      "difficulty": "beginner"
    },
    {
      "question": "2. In size exclusion chromatography, molecules are separated on the basis of their",
      "answers": {
        "a": "Molecular weight",
        "b": "Hydrodynamic volume",
        "c": "Charge",
        "d": "Adsorptive properties"
      },
      
      "correctAnswer": "b",
      "difficulty": "beginner"
    },
    {
      "question": "3. Effective separation of the protein sample through the size exclusion chromatography column depends on a number of factors ",
      "answers": {
        "a": "Pore size",
        "b": "Viscosity of sample and buffer",
        "c": "Packing density of the column",
        "d": "All of the above"
      },
      
      "correctAnswer": "d",
      "difficulty": "beginner"
    },
    {
      "question": "4. What do you mean by resolution in size exclusion chromatography?",
      "answers": {
        "a": "The degree of separation between peaks ",
        "b": "Range of separation of the column",
        "c": "Efficiency of the column media to produce narrow and sharp peak",
        "d": "Both (a) and (c)"
      },
      
      "correctAnswer": "d",
      "difficulty": "beginner"
    },
    {
      "question": "5. In size exclusion chromatography proteins are detected by measuring their absorbance at",
      "answers": {
        "a": "260 nm",
        "b": "300 nm",
        "c": "280 nm",
        "d": "500 nm"
      },
      
      "correctAnswer": "c",
      "difficulty": "beginner"
    },
    {
      "question": "6. Application of size exclusion chromatography are",
      "answers": {
        "a": "Isolate one or more components from a protein mixture",
        "b": "Determine molecular weight of the protein",
        "c": "Buffer exchange and desalting",
        "d": "All of the above"
      },
      
      "correctAnswer": "d",
      "difficulty": "beginner"
    },
    {
      "question": "7. Chromatographic media used for size exclusion chromatography are chosen on the basis of",
      "answers": {
        "a": "Inertness",
        "b": "Chemical and physical stability",
        "c": "None of the above",
        "d": "Both (a) and (b)"
      },
      
      "correctAnswer": "d",
      "difficulty": "beginner"
    },
    {
      "question": "8. Molecules that do not enter the chromatography matrix are eluted ",
      "answers": {
        "a": "In the void volume",
        "b": "When one column volume of buffer has passed through the column",
        "c": "When half column volume  of buffer has passed through the column",
        "d": "None of the above"
      },
      
      "correctAnswer": "a",
      "difficulty": "beginner"
    },
    {
      "question": "9. Fractionation range of a column matrix means",
      "answers": {
        "a": "Range of molecular weights that have partial access to the pores of the particle and can be separated",
        "b": "Size of the molecules that are excluded from the pores",
        "c": "Molecules that elute in the void volume",
        "d": "Selectivity of the matrix"
      },
      
      "correctAnswer": "a",
      "difficulty": "beginner"
    },
    {
      "question": "10. What might be one of the possible reasons behind a blocked column ?",
      "answers": {
        "a": "Protein precipitation in the column",
        "b": "Column is not equilibrated properly",
        "c": "Column is overloaded with sample",
        "d": "Both (a) and (c)"
      },
      
      "correctAnswer": "d",
      "difficulty": "beginner"
    }
  ]
}
